{
    "id": "584e235a886d49bba8d24b736a81d25d",
    "title": "Color Idioms",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Yesterday’s ……………………. was due to unexpected problems with electricity production.",
            "description": "Black out: loss of electricity complete darkening of a room when lights are put out sudden loss of memory",
            "answers": [
                "black out",
                "black off",
                "black in"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e00ca808def1443a9c88df03ddb32295"
        },
        {
            "question": "Susie will go ……………………….. with envy when she sees your new car.",
            "description": "To go green with envy is to be very jealous of objects belonging to other people.",
            "answers": [
                "red",
                "blue",
                "green"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ed53001dcc754d699372470d4bd9b083"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is not the kind of guy you can depend on when you are in trouble. He’s ……………………..",
            "description": "Be yellow means be a coward.",
            "answers": [
                "white",
                "black",
                "yellow"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "28ea4b9c5a84426b9c19ddd168d9952e"
        },
        {
            "question": "A lot of people want to adopt babies. It is the ……………………….. tape that discourages them.",
            "description": "Red tape = delay in public affairs because there is too much attention to rules.",
            "answers": [
                "red",
                "black",
                "dark"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "67bb84cf552f492a814f034b42544588"
        },
        {
            "question": "James was neither brilliant nor hardworking. His Dad always treated him like a ………………………….. sheep.",
            "description": "Black sheep = person of bad character",
            "answers": [
                "red",
                "white",
                "black"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "5b927c3e524943f0a29fa3f7410cb5d3"
        },
        {
            "question": "Mr. Mathews is going to take over as the next chairman. Be sure to roll out the ………………………….. carpet when he arrives.",
            "description": "Roll out the red carpet = Give the best treatment",
            "answers": [
                "blue",
                "red",
                "green"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9061aa95dd0d487fad770d1b12619b23"
        },
        {
            "question": "They have just purchased a new home in the ………………………… belt.",
            "description": "Green belt = the countryside around a city",
            "answers": [
                "blue",
                "green",
                "white"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "93a3f1409f53479fa25aa079dd2855e8"
        },
        {
            "question": "The situation is not as ……………………….. as you think.",
            "description": "Black and white = When something is black and white, it is clear, simple and understandable.",
            "answers": [
                "black",
                "white",
                "black and white"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9cca15c03c814eb6bcf1a04b3a72923e"
        },
        {
            "question": "I’m feeling rather …………………………… these days. Have you got something to cheer me up?",
            "description": "To feel blue is to be depressed.",
            "answers": [
                "grey",
                "blue",
                "pink"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "89ff9570213b4d199c74a0d804a32eb0"
        },
        {
            "question": "He had to tell a ……………………………. lie to escape his mother’s punishment.",
            "description": "White lie = A small insignificant lie.",
            "answers": [
                "blue",
                "white",
                "black"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b37ca942db2c4656834848c75d6e105e"
        },
        {
            "question": "The civil authority has given the ………………………… light to the project.",
            "description": "Give the green light = To give the green light is to approve a project.",
            "answers": [
                "green",
                "blue",
                "white"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7a8c674ddd0746eab8f7f67073f911d6"
        }
    ]
}